Guide to the William Bird Ezra Pound Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
William Bird Ezra Pound papers
1900-1926
YCAL MSS 178
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
2.38
(5 boxes) + 1 broadside folder
Correspondence, writings, personal papers and musical compositions by Ezra Pound dating from his sojourn in Paris during the early 1920s.
Bird, William, 1888-1963
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from Sally Wilson Hall, Ann Remington Southerland and Thomas W. Wilson III in 1977. For further information, consult the appropriate curator.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Box 5: Restricted fragile material. Reference surrogates have been substituted in the main files. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
WILLIAM BIRD, 1888 or 1889-1963
William Augustus Bird was born in Buffalo, New York, on or about January 2, 1889. He graduated from Trinity College, Hartford in 1912 and became a journalist in New York City, where he married Sarah (Sally) Costello. In 1920, he and longtime friend David Lawrence founded the Consolidated Press Service, and Bird moved with his family to Paris to take charge of the office there. They were to remain in France for 20 years.
Shortly after arriving in Paris, Bird became interested in the "hobby" of hand printing, bought a full set of Caslon type, and began printing brief works, including his own A Practical Guide to French Wines (1922). He moved the press into offices at 29, quai d'Anjou and announced the formation of Three Mountains Press; the colophon stylized both his initials and the three mountains of Paris and carried a verse from Psalm 121, "Levavi oculos meos in montes."
In April 1922, Bird met fellow journalist Ernest Hemingway as they were traveling to the Conferenza Internazionale Economica de Genova; he suggested that Bird contact a friend of his, American poet Ezra Pound. Pound immediately began to argue that Bird should "print the MODERNS." Bird agreed, appointing Pound editor of Three Mountains.
Between April 1923 and the end of 1925, Three Mountains Press published nine works. They included Indiscretions, Antheil and the Treatise on Harmony, and A Draft of XVI Cantos by Ezra Pound; The Great American Novel by William Carlos Williams; in our time by Ernest Hemingway; and Distinguished Air by Robert McAlmon. In addition, Bird provided free office space to Ford Madox Ford for the founding of transatlantic review.
Bird lost interest in the press, however. In 1928 he sold his handpress and typecases to Nancy Cunard and supervised its transportation to her home at Réanville, where it became the press for her Hours Press. In the following year, he sold his remaining stock of unsold books to "an American named Schwartz" for $150.00.
Bird continued his successful career as a journalist. He covered Admiral Byrd's flight over the North Pole from Spitzbergen in 1926, and in 1928 became president of the Anglo-American Press Association. The Consolidated Press Service was dissolved in 1933, and Bird joined the New York Sun as chief foreign correspondent. Bird and his family fled to Spain after the fall of France in 1940; in July of that year he wrote a series of articles for the Sun warning Americans war with Hitler was imminent.
After World War II the Birds moved to Tangier, where he was appointed an American representative to the Legislative Assembly of the Tangier International Zone in 1948. He was the editor of the English-language Tangier Gazette until 1960, when the Moroccan government, which had assumed authority over Tangier in 1956-57, closed the newspaper. Bird returned to France, where he died in Paris in August, 1963. He was survived by his daughter, Ann France Bird Wilson.
Scope and Contents
The William Bird Ezra Pound Papers consist of part of the contents of a never-retrieved trunk stored by Pound with William Bird when Pound moved from Paris to Italy in 1924. (Other material from this trunk is now located at the Lilly Library, University of Indiana at Bloomington.) The papers span the dates 1900-1926, although most of the material dates from between 1921 and 1924. They have been organized into four series: I. Correspondence; II. Writings; III. Personal Papers; and IV. Music.
Series I, Correspondence, is alphabetically correspondent and contains both letters received by Pound during his years in Paris and some carbons of his replies. Most correspondents are represented by one or two letters addressing a specific business or literary matter; these include such figures as Granville Bantock, Fanny Butcher, R. W. Chapman, Peggy Guggenheim, Alice Corbin Henderson, Fernand Léger, Samuel Roth, and Ernest Walsh. A carbon of a Pound letter to Maxwell Bodenheim, found in folder 4, contains Pound's comments on Bodenheim's interpretations of "Homage to Sextus Propertius" and "Hugh Selwyn Mauberley." A lengthy letter from Robert McAlmon discusses T. S. Eliot's limitations as a poet and his "intellectual tired adolescent quality" and comments that perhaps Pound has "spent too much time 'doing your share for others.'"
Pound's lifelong interest in physiological theories about mood and temperament is reflected in his correspondence with "gland theorist" Louis Berman (Box 1, folder 3); a carbon of his initial letter to Berman expounds his beliefs about the importance of the pineal gland in creativity. Letters from Agnes Bedford, the English musician with whom Pound collaborated on The Testament of François Villon, include references to that work and descriptions of concerts by George Antheil and Olga Rudge that Bedford attended in London.
Folder 26 contains letters and enclosures from the Japanese artist Tami Koumé (Tamijuro Kume). Koumé discusses plans for a Paris exhibition of his work and an eventual return to Japan; his planned marriage to a Frenchwoman; and his views on Japanese culture and art. A letter dated April 11, 1921 attempts to explain Zen to Pound: "ZEN means nothing! & everything. Without bodyly experience ZEN is nothing!"
The series also includes letters from Pound's publishers Boni & Liveright and Elkin Mathews, some accompanied by recent royalty statements. An October 1922 letter from Horace Liveright is addressed to "Dear Ezry" and comments on the low royalties to date: "I wish to Christ I knew how to sell your books.... Your time will come, but I hope that it won't take as long as it took for Samuel Butler." There are also letters connected to the Pounds' move to 70 bis, rue Notre Dame des Champs late in 1921, including correspondence with carpenters and plumbers concerning household repairs and improvements.
Letters to Pound from his English friend Bride Scratton are located in folders 45-49. Scratton, whose marriage was failing, visited Pound in Paris in 1921 and 1922, and Pound was named co-respondent in the 1923 Scratton divorce. Scratton's letters are highly personal in nature, and contain arrangements for meetings with Pound; description of her negotiations with her husband Ned and her concern for her children; mentions of her fear that she and Pound are being followed by detectives in Paris; and references to her feelings for Pound. In a letter of December 12, 1921 she writes that "It would be very ennuyant for both of us if I got to the stage of not being able to do without you, which is what I'm beginning to feel." There are several letters referring to Dorothy Pound's hospitalization in December 1921, which caused a postponement in a planned visit; an undated letter from this time refers to "a very cross letter" Scratton received from Pound and continues "You are stupid not to understand how much I want you." Finally, letters from 1923 refer to the imminent divorce, the Cantos manuscripts that Pound had sent to Scratton, and the possibility of a future meeting in Italy.
Series II, Writings, is organized into three subseries: Writings in English, Writings in French, and Writings of Others. The first, Writings in English, contains extensive holograph and typescript drafts of Pound's earliest Cantos, as well as the corrected setting typescript for A Draft of XVI Cantos, in which they first appeared. Other writings include the original typescript draft of Antheil and the Treatise on Harmony; a printed copy of "Bel esprit," Pound's appeal for funds to support T. S. Eliot; and an incomplete setting copy for Poems 1918-1921.
The second subseries, Writings in French, is housed in folders 103-121 and contains holograph and typescript draft translations by Pound of some of his shorter poems into French. The material is arranged alphabetically by title of draft. Folder 120 contains a typescript of a collection of such translations; titles are listed in the order in which they appear in the typescript. The third subseries, Writings of Others, contains typescripts of two unidentified poems.
Series III, Personal Papers, is housed in folders 124-144 and includes a copy of Pound's citation as co-respondent in the Scratton divorce case; his 1919 passport; photographs, including a portrait of Thaddeus Pound; printed material and notes by Pound relating to concerts by Antheil; an astrological chart in Pound's hand; and miscellaneous notes, bills and receipts.
Series IV, Music, is housed in box 4 and consists of manuscript music sketches and scores, primarily for Le Testament de Villon, the opera composed by Pound with assistance from the pianist Agnes Bedford. Folders 148-149 contain "Fiddle Music," sketches for a violin suite Pound composed for Olga Rudge, and folder 159 contains violin music in the hand of George Antheil.
Adultery; American literature -- 20th Century; American poetry -- 20th Century; Modernism (Literature); Music and literature; Poets, American -- 20th Century; Authors; Antheil, George, 1900-1959; Bedford, Agnes; Berman, Louis, 1893-1946; Bird, William, 1888-1963; Gould Adams Scratton, B. M. (Bride M.); Kume, Tamijuro; McAlmon, Robert, 1896-1956; Pound, Ezra, 1885-1972 -- Friends and associates; Pound, Ezra, 1885-1972 -- Homes and haunts -- France -- Paris; Pound, Ezra, 1885-1972 -- Relations with women; Pound, Ezra, 1885-1972; Pound, Ezra, 1885-1972 ( Cantos, Canto 1-30); Pound, Ezra, 1885-1972 ( Testament of François Villon); Villon, Francois, 1431-1463 -- Musical settings; Three Mountains Press
- Correspondence, 1920-1924; Series I; 0.42; (1 box)
  Scope and Contents
  Series I, Correspondence, is arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent.
  - Bantock, Granville, 1922 Dec 10 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Bedford, Agnes, 1922-24, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    With holograph notes on Voltaire
  - Berman, Louis, 1922, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Includes typescript carbon of letter from Pound to Lewellys F. Barker, 1922 Mar 1
  - Bodenheim, Maxwell, [1922] (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Boni & Liveright, 1920-23 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Includes letters from Horace Liveright and royalty statements
  - Butcher, Fanny, 1923 Feb 21 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - C. Babin, Serrurerie, Charpentes..., 1923 Jun (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Casati, Luisa, Marchesa, [1923?] (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Cassou, Jean, 1922 Mar 20 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Chapman, R. W., 1921 Feb 21 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Typescript carbon of letter to "Messrs. Watt and Sons" concerning Pound
  - Cook, Howard Willard, 1923 Jul 31 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Cros, Guy-Charles, 1924 Jun 26 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    With: "Montparnasse. Pour Ezra Pound," holograph
  - Elkin Mathews, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Elson, H. P., 1923 Dec 4 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    With: printed circular letter by Elson concerning the "Raymond Lull Home" in Tangier and printed poem by John Martin Cleaver, "For Thee"
  - Fairfax, J. Griffyth, 1922 Mar 23 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Fowler, [Mrs. Alfred?], 1922 Jun 22 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    Concerning a José Maria dos Santos
  - Gebrüder Drucker, 1922 Oct 31 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    To Nancy Fairburn
  - Gilmore, Louis, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 18)
    Typescript of a title page with holograph request for suggestions
  - Gorman, Herbert S., 1923 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Guggenheim, Peggy, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    Signed "Peggy Vail"
  - Heath and Co., [ca. 1922] (Box 1, Folder 21)
    With "MEMO for American Agent," typescript carbon
  - Henderson, Alice Corbin, 1921 Feb 13 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Herbert, George, 1921-23 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Holbrooke, Joseph, n.y. Feb 3 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Kettelwell, John, 1922 Mar 14 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Koumé, Tami, 1921-23 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    Includes typescript of haiku in English signed by Koumé; calling card; printed invitations to a tea held by Koumé, Pound and J. Brinkley, [1922] Jul 11; and small wash drawing on paper by Koumé (Tamijuro Kume)
  - Knopf, Alfred. A., n.d. (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - [Kreymborg], Alfred, [1922] (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Léger, Fernand, 1922 Aug 19 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Liveright, Horace B.
    Related Archival Materials note
    See: Boni & Liveright, Box 1, folder 5
  - Lyon, Fred M., 1922 Dec 13 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Marchetti, Averardo, 1923 Jun 12 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    With mourning card
  - McAlmon, Robert, 1922, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    Letter of 1922 Nov 28 accompanied by note from William Bird to Pound
  - McCormack, Nancy Cox, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Miró, Joan, 1923 Dec 31 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Monroe, Harriet, 1923 Jul 8 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Myers, Ruth H., n.y. Oct 14 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Nicaise, Henri, 1923 Sep 29 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Orage, A. R. (Alfred Richard), 1921, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Picabia, Francis, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Quinn, John, n.y. Jul 4 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Reyber, Ferdinand, 1921 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    With cancelled check and TLS to Nancy Cox McCormack from the Equitable Company of New York, 1921
  - Reynolds, Mary, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Roth, Samuel, n.y. Jul 4 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Schelling, Felix, 1922 Jul 8 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    Letter from Pound
  - Scratton, Bride, 1921 Oct (Box 1, Folder 45)
    With: ALS from unidentified to Pound concerning detectives following Scratton, n.d.
    With: ALS from Scratton to Mrs. Victor Rickard, 1921 Oct 6
  - Scratton, Bride, 1921 Nov-Dec (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Scratton, Bride, 1922 Jan-Feb (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Scratton, Bride, 1922 Mar-Apr (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Scratton, Bride, 1922 Jul-Nov (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Seltzer, Thomas, 1922 May 9 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Strater, Henry, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Sturgis, Frank, 1922 Nov 18 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - United States. Embassy (France), 1923 Dec 18 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Walsh, Ernest, 1922 Nov 24 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Watson, J. Sibley, 1923, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Unidentified, 1922, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Empty envelopes, 1921-23, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 57-58)
- Writings, 1922-1926; Series II; 0.63; (1.5 boxes)
  Series II, Writings, is organized into three subseries: Writings in English, Writings in French, and Writings of Others. Each subseries is alphabetically arranged by title of work.
  - WRITINGS IN ENGLISH
    - Antheil and the Treatise on Harmony, [1922-24] (Box 2, Folder 59-63)
      Typescript and typescript carbon, with extensive holograph corrections and interpolations
    - "Bel Esprit", n.d. (Box 2, Folder 64)
      Printed leaflet
    - Canto I: Ur-Canto I, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 65)
      Typescript, corrected
    - Canto I, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 66)
      Typescript, incomplete
    - Canto II, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 67)
      Typescript with holograph additions and corrections
    - Canto II, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 68)
      - Typescript, with holograph annotations [concerning "The Waste Land"]
    - Canto II [beginning and end] (Box 2, Folder 69)
      Typescript with holograph annotations
    - Canto III, end (Box 2, Folder 70)
      Typescript Opens: "Drear waste, great halls"
    - Canto III, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 71)
    - Canto IV, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 72)
      Holograph and typescript, incomplete
    - Canto VI, V, XXII, XXIX??, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 73)
      Typescripts, incomplete
    - Canto VI, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 74)
      Typescript with holograph annotations, incomplete
    - Canto VIII, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 75)
    - Canto VIII, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 76)
    - Canto IX (later VIII), n.d. (Box 2, Folder 77)
      Holograph
    - Canto XII (headed X) (Box 2, Folder 78)
      - Holograph, incomplete, n.d.
    - Canto XII (headed X), n.d. (Box 2, Folder 79)
    - Canto XII, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 80)
    - Cantos XIII, XII, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 81)
      Proof sheets
    - Canto XIII, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 82)
    - Canto XIII, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 83)
      Holograph and typescript fragments
    - Canto XIII, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 84)
      Typescript with holograph corrections and annotations
    - Canto XIV, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 85)
      Typescript fragment
    - Cantos XIV-XV, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 86)
      Typescripts with holograph corrections
    - Cantos XIV, XVI, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 87)
      Holographs
    - Canto XV, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 88)
      Holograph, incomplete With: AL (draft) to "T" [T. S. Eliot], n.d.
    - Canto XV, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 89)
      Typescript
    - Canto XVI [and following] (Box 2, Folder 90)
      Typescript with holograph corrections and additions
    - Canto XVI, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 91)
    - A Draft of XVI Cantos, [1924] (Box 2, Folder 92)
      Setting copy for the Malatesta Cantos: typescript with holograph annotations and directions for the printer
    - Canto XXVIII, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 93)
      Typescript with holograph corrections
    - Canto XXIX, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 94)
    - Canto XXX, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 95)
    - Canto [?], n.d. (Box 2, Folder 96)
      [False start for Canto X, containing lines later found in VII]
    - Cantos, unidentified, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 97)
      Holograph notes
    - "The Exile", n.d. (Box 3, Folder 98)
    - ["The Ideograph"], n.d. (Box 3, Folder 99)
    - Personae, 1926 (Box 3, Folder 100)
      Unbound, uncut gatherings of pp. 11-18, 13-16
    - Poems 1918-1921, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 101)
      Setting copy, incomplete
    - "The Vorticists", n.d. (Box 3, Folder 102)
  - WRITINGS IN FRENCH
    - "Au Jardin", n.d. (Box 3, Folder 103)
    - "Dans un omnibus de Londres" (Box 3, Folder 104)
      Holograph and typescript, corrected, incomplete
    - "La Fraisne", n.d. (Box 3, Folder 105)
    - "Further Instructions (Conseils supplémentaires)", n.d. (Box 3, Folder 106)
      Holograph and typescript
    - "The Garden", n.d. (Box 3, Folder 107)
      Manuscript and typescript drafts
    - "A Girl (L'Arbre (Une Mademoiselle)", n.d. (Box 3, Folder 108)
    - "The Gypsy", n.d. (Box 3, Folder 109)
    - "In Durance" (Box 3, Folder 110)
    - "Marveil", n.d. (Box 3, Folder 111)
    - "Mr. Housman's Message", n.d. (Box 3, Folder 112)
    - "Piere Vidal Old, l. 1-12", n.d. (Box 3, Folder 113)
    - "Sage Homme", n.d. (Box 3, Folder 114)
    - "A Study in Aesthetics", n.d. (Box 3, Folder 115)
    - "Simulacra (Des Questions)", n.d. (Box 3, Folder 116)
    - "Tenzone", n.d. (Box 3, Folder 117)
    - "Threnos", n.d. (Box 3, Folder 118)
    - "Le type national", n.d. (Box 3, Folder 119)
      Holograph and typescript, annotated
    - Typescript of various translations, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 120)
      Includes translations of:
      "In a Station of the Metro" "Hokku"
      "Pagani's SNN"
      "Liu chee"
      "Heather"
      "The Game of Chess"
      "The Social Order"
      "Salvationists II"
      "The Temperaments"
      "Les Millures"
      "Ancora"
      "The Faun"
      "The Bath Tub"
      "The Condolence"
      "The Patterns"
      "Phyllidula"
      "Meditatio"
      "The Encounter"
      "Ladies [III]"
      "Tempora"
      "The Three Poets"
    - Unidentified and incomplete typescripts (Box 3, Folder 121)
  - WRITINGS OF OTHERS
    - "At Fuenterrabia in Spain", n.d. (Box 3, Folder 122)
      Typescript mimeograph of unidentified poem: "God/Loves gold/In his churches..."
    - "Dedication", n.d. (Box 3, Folder 123)
      Typescript of unidentified poem: "Brown of cedar, gray of aspen..."
- Personal Papers, 1900-1926; Series III; 0.21; (1/2 box)
  Series III, Personal Papers, is alphabetically arranged by type of material.
  - Artwork, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 124)
    Pencil sketches of Ezra Pound and other subjects; pencil and watercolor head of a woman
  - Bills and receipts, 1922-23 (Box 3, Folder 125-126)
  - "Calendar for Year I. p.s.u.", [1922?] (Box 3, Folder 127)
    Astrological calendar charts, holographs With holograph map of the Near East
  - Copy citation of Pound as correspondent in Scratton v. Scratton divorce case, 1922 Nov 29 (Box 3, Folder 128)
    Accompanied by an official copy of the divorce petition
  - Notepad with miscellaneous holograph notes, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 129)
  - Notes, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 130)
    Miscellaneous brief holograph notes, most in Pound's hand
  - Passport, 1919 Jul (Box 3, Folder 131)
  - Photographs, n.d.
    - Cocteau, Jean, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 132)
    - Foster, Jeanne Robert, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 133)
    - Huth, Helen Rose (Mrs. Louis), n.d. (Box 3, Folder 134)
    - Pound, Dorothy (Box 3, Folder 135)
    - Pound, Ezra (Box 3, Folder 136)
    - Pound, Thaddeus C., 1900 May 10 (Box 3, Folder 137)
    - Unidentified child, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 138)
    - Unidentified man with goat, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 139)
    - Unidentified building, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 140)
  - Postcards, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 141)
  - Social Credit, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 142)
    Printed copy of "The Social Credit Proposals" with typescript commentary by Pound on verso ("Izzis comprehensible/ ?? Andy Jax/ and Marty V.B. did No. I...." With typescript notes
  - "Special invitation to the Press" for a private performance of George Antheil's "Ballet Mécanique", 1926 Jul (Box 3, Folder 143)
    Printed
  - Tickets for the Rudge-Antheil concert at the Salle du Conservatiore, 1923 Dec 11 (Box 3, Folder 144)
    With holograph and typescript drafts by Pound of program for event
- Music, 1924; Series IV; 0.92; (1 box)
  Arrangement
  Series IV, Music, is arranged alphabetically by title of composition.
  - "Collis of Heliconii" (sketch), n.d. (Box 4, Folder 145)
    Holograph; early draft of beginning of the opera "Cavalcanti"
  - "Dux" (solo violin); holograph, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 146)
  - "Era nel core" [sketch of piece for solo violin]; holograph, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 147)
  - "Fiddle music;" holograph sketches, 1924 Mar (Box 4, Folder 148)
  - "Fiddle music;" holograph sketches, [1924] (Box 4, Folder 149)
  - "Folle e colui che vole;" holograph sketch for solo violin, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 150)
  - "Sestina: Alta forte;" holograph sketch., n.d. (Box 4, Folder 151)
    Scored for violin and drum.
  - The Testament of François Villon; holograph sketches and full score (Box 4, Folder 152)
    Inclues vocal score for "Hëaulmière", "Dictes Moy," and "Mort j'appelle"
  - The Testament of François Villon; holograph sketches, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 153)
  - The Testament of François Villon; holograph sketches, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 154)
    Some in Agnes Bedford's hand
  - The Testament of François Villon; holograph sketches, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 155)
  - The Testament of François Villon; holograph sketches, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 156)
  - "Violin music;" holograph sketches and studies (Box 4, Folder 157)
  - "Violin music;" holograph sketches and studies (Box 4, Folder 158)
  - "Violin music lessons;" holograph, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 159)
    In George Antheil's hand
  - Miscellaneous music sketches, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 160)
    Includes transcriptions of troubadour music.
  - [Pound notes on The Testament of François Villon ?] (Box 6, Folder bsd)
- Restricted Fragile
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted fragile material. Reference surrogates have been substituted in the main files. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
  - Box 1, folder 3 (Box 5, Folder 161)
  - Box 1, folder 19 (Box 5, Folder 162)